

SKILLS

Design Tools:

Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Final Cut Video Editor

Front-End

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React

Development

Git, REST API, Node.js, Agile Methodology

ABOUT ME

I'm a UX/UI Designer and Junior Front-End Developer with a unique background in architecture.

My 7+ years of experience in physical and digital design give me a distinctive perspective in crafting functional, usercentered solutions. Known for my strong communication skills, adaptability, and attention to detail, I'm always eager to stay updated with industry trends to deliver innovative results.

CONTACT

+34

+34 663-585081

M

mariacv1993@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/mariacortesv24/



github.com/Mariacortesv

0

Barcelona, Spain

María Cortés Vargas

UX/UI DESIGNER | FRONT END DEVELOPER JUNIOR

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer Sizigia Consulting May. 2024 - Now Barcelona, Spain (Remote)

Designed responsive websites and mobile apps, prioritizing user experience and accessibility while collaborating with clients and developers to lead wireframe creation and enhance user engagement.

ARCHITECT

Feb. 2021- Oct. 2023 (2 yrs-9 mos) Barcelona, Spain

Roarquitectos

Interior design for new construction and renovation projects, including measurements, budgeting, and energy efficiency certifications.

COMMUNITY MANAGER HIPER MONTIGALA SL

Oct. 2021- May 2022 (8 mos) Badalona, Spain

Active management of social media and website, crafting engaging content and promotional materials. Supervision of sales and shipments, ensuring effective communication for customer satisfaction.

ARCHITECT

Ministry of Education of the Dominican Republic

Jan. 2017- Dec. 2020 (4 yrs) Santo Domingo, DR

Surveying and design of plans for Public Schools in the country. Conducting measurements and proposing construction or rehabilitation plans, as well as preparing improvement reports.

EDUCATION

UXCEL 2023-2024 UX/UI Design Barcelona, Spain

Develhope2023-2024
Full Stack Developer
Barcelona, Spain

EINA2020 - 2021
Master's in Space Design, User Experience
Barcelona, Spain

PUCMM 2011 - 2017
Architecture Santo Domingo, DR

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)

English (TOEFL)



Català (A2)

